Once in a lifetime comes the perfect killer
Crying Freeman is a action, crime film directed by Christophe Gans.
A lethal assassin for a secret Chinese organisation, who sheds tears of regret each time he kills, is
seen swiftly and mercilessly executing three Yakuza gangsters by a beautiful artist.
She is captivated by the grace of his kill and later falls in love with him.
An intense power struggle for the leadership of the Yakuza Clans ensues
as they seek vengeance for the death of their leader.
Yo Hinomura / Freeman, played by Mark Dacascos.
Emu O'Hara, played by Julie Condra.
Detective Forge, played by Rae Dawn Chong.
Koh, played by Byron Mann.
Ryuji Hanada, played by Masaya Katō.
Lady Hanada, played by Yoko Shimada.
Crying Freeman is a 1995 action film, based on the manga of the
same name by Kazuo Koike and Ryoichi Ikegami.
It is directed and co-written by Christophe Gans in his solo directorial debut and stars Mark Dacascos in the title
role, a brainwashed assassin for a Triad secret society, who sheds a tear for every victim he kills.
Tchéky Karyo, Julie Condra, Byron Mann, Masaya Kato, Yoko
Shimada, and Mako play supporting roles.
The film was an international co-production between France, Canada, and Japan,
and was filmed on location in British Columbia in October 1994.
Despite being heavily promoted by Viz Media in Animerica magazine and reprints of the Crying Freeman graphic
novel, the film was not released in the United States until November 2018 on Amazon Prime Video.
The film explores themes of hitman, fight, yakuza, artist, falling in love.
The tone is intense.